Guide to the Oral History of the American Left Collection OH.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I. Oral History of the American Left Main Series, 1940-2011
  - John Shenton -- Transcript, Jun 20, 1967; cuid1499 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    Interview covers the activities of the Socialist Party in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1920s-1960s.
  - Moishe Shik, Dec 27, 1982; cuid1500
    - Access Copy (Box 25, Cd Shik 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 234)
  - Anne Shore, May 12, 1982 - Jun 15, 1982; cuid1501
    Interview covers the activities of the Communist Party, the activities of the United Office and Professional Workers of America (UOPWA), picketing of the Nazi ship the Bremen, Shore's experiences in Detroit during the the 1940s, the Civil Rights Congress and Progressive Party in Los Angeles during the late 1940s through early 1950s, the effects of McCarthy period on the left, and Shore's work for Local 1199 (Hospital Workers) during the 1960s.
    Interview by Priscilla Backman.
    - Access Copy (Box 25, Cd Shore 1-8)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 235 A-H)
  - Meyer Shticker, undated; cuid1502
    - Access Copy (Box 25, Cd Shticker 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 405)
  - Elias Shulman, Oct 19, 1982; cuid1503
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Shulman 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 300)
  - Robert J. Silberstein and Howard Meyer, Jun 22, 1982; cuid1504
    Interview covers the activities International Labor Defense and the National Lawyers Guild from the 1930s-1940s.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Silberstein and Meyer 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 236A-B)
  - Fanny Simon, Feb 12, 1982; cuid1506
    Interview documents the activities of the Socialist Party during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd F. Simon 1-2)
    - Original recording, cuid43244 (Box 77, Audiocassette 237A)
    - Original recording, cuid43245 (Box 77, Audiocassette 237B)
      Preservation note: Audio is muted, side 2 is blank.
  - Madeline Simon, Nov 15, 2002; cuid1505
    Interview contains Simon's reminiscences on Camp Kinderland and a discussion of music and Yiddishkeit.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd M. Simon 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 237.1A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Donald Slaiman, Dec 16, 1994; cuid1507
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Slaiman 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 341)
  - Jessie Taft Smith, Nov 19, 1981; cuid1508
    Interview covers Smith's family background in Norwalk, Connecticut during the 1910s-1920s, the activities of the Young Communist League, the laundry workers' union, and Smith's social and political life in the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Smith 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 238A-B)
  - Richard Soble, Mar 31, 1983; cuid1509
    Interview documents radical legal work in Detroit during the 1960s-1970s (including "Red Squad" lawsuit) and a late 1960s rent strike.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Soble 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 239)
  - Socialist Labor Party, Mar 17, 1983; cuid1510
    Interview regarding Socialist Labor Party "South Slavonian" language federation during the 1920s-1950s in Detroit and Cleveland. Interviewees include John Brlas, Mary Petrovich-Brlas, Vito DeLisi, Mary Korach, and Matt Korach.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Socialist Labor Party 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 240 A-D)
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress, Feb 6, 1984; cuid1511
    Forum on the history of the Southern Negro Youth Congress featuring one-time SNYC activists Henry Winston, James Jackson, Grace Tillman Bassett, Esther Jackson, and Dorothy Burnham.
    Duration: 120 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd SNYC 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 241A-B)
  - Spanish Civil War Poetry, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1512
    Digital transfer of the the second side of the second cassette was not possible due to poor condition of the tape.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd 418A-B)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 418A-B)
  - Anton Srok, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1513
    Interview covers the Srok's experiences in the Milwaukee Croatian Fraternal Union, 1930s-1980s and his labor activities in Milwaukee during 1930s. Srok also describes his experiences as an amateur Croatian-American actor in Milwaukee.
    Duration: 71 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Srok 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 242A-B)
  - Sid Stein & Eugene Dennis, Dec 1957; cuid1514
    Speech by Sid Stein from a debate with Eugene Dennis at CPUSA Executive Committee.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Stein 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 325)
  - Charlotte Stern, May 7, 1979; cuid1515
    Interview regarding Stern's experiences as member of the executive board of Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee from 1944-1950. Second CD and cassette contains 2:56 of unrelated material on first track or side.
    Interview by Dorothy Swanson.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd C. Stern 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 330 A-B)
  - Sholem Stern, Sep 18, 1978; cuid1516
    Stern describes his experiences as a radical Yiddish writer and poet in Montreal and New York during the 1920s-1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd S. Stern 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 243)
  - Sholem Stern, undated; cuid1517
    Discussion includes comments on Morgen Freiheit, Yiddishe Kultur, and other Yiddish literary outlets. Interview also includes discussion of prominent Yiddish writers and the relationship between literature, the Jewish left, and the Communist Party.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd S. Stern 2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 406)
  - Morton Stavis, Dec 9, 1991 - Jan 21, 1992; cuid1518
    Topics discussed include Stavis' youth on the Lower East Side, education at City College and Columbia Law School, Social Security Administration, unionism and civil rights, working with Senator Wagner, the War Labor Board, Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, Carl and Anne Braden, the Center for Constitutional Rights, and civil rights cases. Two specific cases covered are the McSurley Case of 1967 (regarding civil rights activists in Pikeville, Kentucky) and Philippines Case of 1986 (regarding property in New York owned by the the Marcos family).
    Interview by Alan Thomson.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Stavis 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 314 A-D)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Isidor Steuzert, Oct 27, 1982; cuid1519
    Interview documents the activities of the Jewish Socialist Federation, the nature of American Communism, and the Lovestoneites.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Steuzert 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 244)
  - Chalmers Stewart, Jun 22, 1983; cuid1520
    Interview contains Stewart's reflections on CLR James.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Stewart 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 382)
  - Chaim Suller, Jan 20, 1983; cuid1521
    Suller describes his background in the Jewish progressive movement and discusses the problems of the Morgen Freiheit in the 1980s.
    Duration: 40 minutes
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Suller 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 245)
  - Elliot Sullivan Memorial Service, undated; cuid1522
    Speakers at this recorded memorial service include Sylvia Thompson, Madeline Lee Gilford, Ralph Elswain, Ruby Dee, Will Lee, Biff Liff, Jane Hoffman, Peter Seeger, and Norma Sullivan.
    - Access Copy (Box 26, Cd Sullivan 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Cd Sullivan 1)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Arne Swabeck, Apr 7, 1975 - Nov 19, 1975; cuid1523
    Series of tapes recorded by John Shannon in the course of researching for an unpublished book. Topics covered in this extensive set of interviews include: childhood, travels, Communist activities, analysis of factional splits in the left from the 1920s onward, and reflections on the left at the time of the interview.
    Interview by John Shannon.
    Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
    Digitization of this interview was not completed, due to the poor quality of the audio and size of the interview. Based on John Shannon's session notes for the interview, these issues likely date to the original recording. Cassettes 246A to 246OO have been digitized. Cassettes 246PP to 246WW have not been digitized.
    To request an access copy of materials in the undigitized portion of this interview, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A librarian will respond to you with further information.
    Original cassettes were donated to Columbia University's Oral History Research Office by John Shannon, and Columbia University also maintains a copy of the interview.
    - Access Copy -- 1 of 2 (Box 27, Cd Swabeck 1-51)
    - Access Copy -- 2 of 2 (Box 28, Cd Swabeck 52-76)
    - Original Recording -- 1 of 2 (Box 77, Audiocassette 246A-G)
    - Original Recording -- 2 of 2 (Box 78, Audiocassette 246H-WW)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Arne Swabeck, Oct 23, 1982; cuid1524
    Interview covers the activities of the Scandinavian Socialist Federation and press.
    Duration: 98 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Swabeck 77-78)
    - Original Recording (Box 77, Audiocassette 246A-B)
  - A.O. Syrstad, Jan 5, 1978; cuid1525
    Interview documents the activities of the Workers Party and the Independent Socialist League in Seattle, Washington during the 1940s-1950s.
    Duration: 44 minutes
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Syrstad 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 247)
  - Loretta Szeliga, Dec 8, 1981; cuid1526
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Szeliga 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 354)
  - Anna Taffler, Jan 5, 1978; cuid1527
    Taffler discusses the activities of the unemployed councils in Brooklyn between 1930 and 1934.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Taffler 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 248A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Stephen Tendler, Oct 5, 1984; cuid1528
    Topics discussed include the activities of the Socialist Labor Party in Saint Louis from the 1930s-1960s, the Bulgarian Federation in Granite City, Illinois, and the reorganization of Section Saint Louis in 1979.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Tendler 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 411)
  - Norman Thomas -- Transcripts, 1960-1966; cuid1529 (Box 8, Folder 39-42)
    Interview contains the reminiscences of Norman Thomas, the six-time Socialist Party candidate for President.
    Interview by Harry Fleischman.
  - Norman Thomas 1932 Campaign, 50th Anniversary, Nov 19, 1982 - Nov 20, 1982; cuid1531
    This recording of a reunion includes speakers Ruth Senior, Mickey Most, Herb Wolfe, John Herling, Noah Walter, and Michael Harrington. Speakers share their recollections of Thomas' first presidential campaign and discuss his career and influence overall.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thomas Campaign 1-6)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 251A-F)
  - Debate between Norman Thomas and Barry Goldwater, 1961; cuid1532
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thomas and Goldwater 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 414)
  - Bessie Thomashow, undated; cuid1533
    Interview documents the activities of the Workmen's Circle during the 1930s.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thomashow 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 253)
  - Fred Thompson, Apr 1983; cuid1534
    Interview regarding the activities of the International Workers of the World after 1924.
    Duration: 89 minutes
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 255)
  - Fred Thompson, Jul 26, 1983; cuid1535
    Interview includes an analysis of the nature of the language federations attached to Industrial Workers of the World, descriptions of prominent immigrant figures in IWW, and commentary on the eclipse of the language federations and ethnic press in the IWW.
    Duration: 87 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thompson 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 254A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Alan Thomson, Feb 11, 1993; cuid1536
    Interview by Stacy Sewell.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thomson 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 327 A-B)
  - Ahrne Thorne, Dec 15, 1983; cuid1537
    Interview documents Thorne's background in Poland, his education as an anarchist, Yiddish anarchism in the United States since the 1920s, the relationship between Yiddish anarchism and Zionism, and Thorne's recollections of Rudolf Rocker.
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thorne 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 256A-B)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Ahrne Thorne, undated; cuid1538
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Thorne 3)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 407)
  - Frank Trager, Nov 21, 1973; cuid1539
    Duration: 98 minutes
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Trager 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 338)
  - Haunani-Kay Trask, undated; cuid1540
    Interview by Joy Shimabukuro
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Trask 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 303A-B)
  - Jerry Trauber, Nov 4, 1979; cuid1541
    - Access Copy (Box 28, Cd Trauber 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 408)
  - Esther Travaglio, Oct 30, 1982; cuid1542
    Interview documents the background and activities of Esther Hartz Travaglio. It also covers the activities of "Gene" Travaglio, an anarchist and job-printer in Seattle and California.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Travaglio 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 257 A-B)
  - Jean Tussey, Oct 24, 1978 - Oct 25, 1978, Mar 20, 1979; cuid1543
    Interview covers Tussey's activities with the Steel Workers Organizing Committee, the Socialist Party, and the Socialist Workers Party in New Jersey and Southern California from the 1930s through the early 1940s.
    Interview by Debra Bernhardt and Jon Bloom.
    Duration: 111 minutes in two parts; Preservation Note: The third audiocassette could not be digitized due to its condition.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Tussey 1-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 259A-C)
    - Transcript (Box 8, Folder 46-47)
  - Uhro Tuominen, Nov 5, 1983; cuid1544
    Interview documents the activities of the "younger" generation of Finnish-American radicals in Midwest and California. Tuominen describes of the tenacity and decline of Finnish-American activity in Bay Area and the effort of Communist and non-Communist Finnish-Americans to engage in common functions.
    Duration: 64 minutes; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Tuominen 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 258)
  - Gus Tyler, Oct 29, 1973; cuid1545
    Duration: 78 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Tyler 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 339 A-B)
  - Tyomies Panel Discussion, Jul 30, 1983; cuid1546
    Panel discussion including Mary Kolehmainen, Helen Kruth, Ernest Koski and other prominent editorial workers on the origins, development, and continuation of Finnish-language newspaper Tyomies (The Worker) and its sister paper Naisten Viiri (Women's Banner). Presentation includes history of paper, government intimidation of newspaper, achievements of Finnish-American press and people, the decline of the circulation, and the development of cooperative movements.
    Discussion recorded by Paul Buhle.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Tyomies 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 260)
  - Unemployed Organizations of the 1930s, Apr 30, 1983; cuid1547
    A recording of a session of a 1983 New York State Labor History Association meeting. Includes a presentation by Roy Rosenzweig, followed by panel discussion with Saul Parker, John Gates, Rose Schuyler, and Brendan Sexton.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Unemployed Organizations 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 78, Audiocassette 261A-B)
  - Unidentified Yiddish-language Poet (originally from Ukraine), Mar 21, 1979; cuid1548
    Narrator speaks about youth in Ukraine and Romania, introduction to poetry, influences (including Russian, Native American, African American, and Roma poetry), his books Flowers in the Snow and Eternally Green, the influence of Marxism on his poetry, and Moshe Nadir.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Unidentified Poet 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 390)
  - Willard Uphaus, Nov 9, 1980; cuid1550
    Recording of Willard Uphaus' 90th birthday celebration, by Bea Lemisch.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Uphaus 3-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 262A-B)
  - Willard Uphaus and Ruth MacLennan, Jul 20, 1983; cuid1549
    Interview documents the lives of Willard and Ruth MacLennan Uphaus, with a special emphasis on their activities in the 1930s. Topics include their meeting, the intersection of their politics and Christianity, their friendship with Claude Williams, and Socialism.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Uphaus 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 304A-B)
  - Vittorio Vidali -- Transcript, Aug 6, 1981; cuid1551 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    Interview covers the activities of the Italian Language Federation and the American Communist movement during the 1920s, Chicago and the Left, and Vidali's reflections on American Communism. Translated from the Italian-language Autobiography of Vittorio Vidali, a document on his years in the United States from 1923 to 1927.
  - Abraham Vishnu & Getzel Becker, Oct 25, 1978; cuid1552
    Interview documents radicalism and culture in New York and Miami Beach, anti-Semitism in the radical movements of Poland, life for Jewish workers in pre-revolutionary Cuba, and the importance of Yiddish culture for political movements from the 1920s-1950s.
    Duration: 124 minutes in two parts; Preservation note: Poor audio quality
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Vishnu & Becker 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 264A-B)
  - Jacob Waisbord, Jun 28, 1993; cuid1553
    Interview regarding the Left Poale Zion and the Jewish Labor Committee.
    Interview by Gail Malmgreen.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Waisbord 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 340A-B)
  - Hershel Walker, undated; cuid1554
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Walker 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 80, Audiocassette 356-357)
  - Frank Wallin, Jul 31, 1983; cuid1555
    Interview documents Wallin's editorial activities from the 1940s-1970s for the Finnish-language paper Tyomies and Industrilistii,, a Finnish-American newspaper affiliated with the International Workers of the World (IWW).
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Wallin 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 266)
  - Albert Warner, May 4-5, 1980; cuid1556
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Warner 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 305 A-B)
  - Susan Warren -- Transcript, Apr 17, 1966; cuid1557 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Interview documents the activities of the Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy and the Jefferson School of Social Science during the 1950s.
  - Arthur Waskow, Apr 2, 1970; cuid1558
    Interview describes activities and internal politics of Students for a Democratic Society. Waskow reflects on its eventual dissolution.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Waskow 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 276)
  - Mary-Alice Waters, undated; cuid1559
    A recording of Mary-Alice Waters' speech titled "Women's Liberation and the Socialist Revolution."
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Waters 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 267)
  - Stan Weir, Dec 28, 1981; cuid1560
    Interview document's Weir's experiences in Los Angeles.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Weir 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 269 A-B)
  - Stan Weir, Oct 22, 1982; cuid1562
    Interview documents Weir's analyses of the activities of C.L.R. James, the Johnson-Forest Tendency, and the Workers Party.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Weir 3-4)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 269C-D)
    - Original Recording
  - Stan Weir, Aug 13, 1983 - Aug 15, 1983; cuid1561
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Weir 5-14)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 269E-J)
  - Louis Weiss, Mar 15, 1983; cuid1564
    Interview includes discussion of Weiss' emigration from Poland, his work as a dress presser, and activities of the The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU).
    Interview also includes commentary from an unidentified woman and unidentified man. The woman speaks to her experience in different progressive and radical organizations during the 1930s-1940s, including the International Labor Defense, American Labor Party, and others.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Weiss 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 10, Audiocassette 384 A-B)
  - Myra Tanner Weiss, 1982; cuid1563
    Interview covers Weiss' family and educational background in Salt Lake City and Los Angeles, the unemployed movement and Trotskyist movement during the 1930s-1940s, anti-fascist demonstrations, and her experiences as Socialist Workers Party candidate during the 1940s-1950s.
    - Access Copy (Box 29, Cd Weiss 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 270)
  - Sam Weiss, Apr 8, 1980; cuid1565
    Interview documents the role of the Freie Arbeter Shtimme (Free Voice of Labor) in the labor movement of the 1920s-1930s and describes activities of anarchists within the Arbeter Ring (Workmens' Circle).
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd S. Weiss 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 271)
  - Saul Wellman - Transcript, Aug 24, 1972; cuid1566 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Interview covers the activities of the Communist Party during the 1930s-1950s, Wellman's reflections on the relationship between the Communist Party and unions, Communists and United Auto Workers during the Second World War, reactions to the Hitler-Stalin Pact, and the Left's activities during the Cold War.
  - Saul Wellman: 65th birthday dinner, 1980; cuid1567
    Duration: 144 minutes in two parts
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Wellman Dinner 1-3)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 273 A-B)
  - Yvette West, Jan 19, 1983; cuid1568
    Interview covers West's family dynamics growing up, her youth in the International Workers of the World (IWW) during the mid-1930s, and the literary career of her father, Yiddish critic B. Rivkin.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd West 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 275A-B)
  - Ed Wiese, Apr 24, 1981; cuid1569
    Interview covers Wiese's work in the Westinghouse Elevator Plant in Jersey City and the influence of the left. It also documents his time as president of Local 456 of the United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America (UE).
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Wiese 1-2)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 274 A-B)
  - Jim Williams, Apr 2, 1970; cuid1570
    Interview regarding the internal politics and activities of Students for a Democratic Society on campuses across the United States. Williams also comments on reasons for the SDS split and the different Marxist factions in the New Left.
    - Access Copy (Box 30, Cd Williams 1)
    - Original Recording (Box 79, Audiocassette 276)
  - Paul W. Williams - Transcript, May 11, 1976; cuid1571 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Interview documents the prosecution of International Workers' Order during the 1950s.
  - Tim Wohlforth - Transcript, Aug 29, 1976; cuid1572 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Interview documents Wohlforth's background in Bridgeport, Connecticut during the 1930s-1940s and Socialism and Trotskyism during the 1950s.
  - Alice Dodge Wolfson, Apr 1, 1982; cuid1573